# **Nikos Kousiadis**

Data Analyst

Galatsi, 11147, Greece
₩ 8th December 1990
(+30) 6945 382 564
nkousiadis@hotmail.com
in Link, Link
Military obligations fulfilled

### About me

A data science enthusiast with demonstrated abilities in manipulating and analyzing data to solve problems, building creative visualizations to gain insights and developing machine learning models to predict business outcomes. Solid skills in mathematics and programming and experience with a variety of relational databases and big data systems. Keen interest in R programming for data science and development of data products with R Shiny to automate analytics processes and present findings.

## **Work Experience**

Data Analyst, Analytics Department, Intelen Inc, Athens	
05/2017 - Present	Tools
<ul> <li>Design, develop and maintain analytics app (R Shiny) for the following purposes: data visualisation, statistical results, simulation, KPI monitoring, customer scoring and segmentation, predictive modelling, etc.</li> </ul>	R PostgreSQL
<ul> <li>Use supervised and unsupervised machine learning methods to optimize customer experience, revenue generation and other business outcomes</li> </ul>	MySQL
Enhance customer experience building recommender systems for personalized services	R Shiny
Develop and automate reporting processes	R Markdown
<ul> <li>Define, measure and monitor KPIs</li> </ul>	git
<ul> <li>Design new data-driven business products</li> </ul>	MS Excel
Data Scientist, Credit Risk Department, ICAP Group, Athens 07/2016 - 05/2017	Tools
	100.5
<ul> <li>Prepare the thesis "Storage of Default Characterization Data", as part of the M.Sc. in Business Analytics, Athens University of Economics and Business</li> </ul>	R
	R SAS Base
Analytics, Athens University of Economics and Business  • Support regulatory requirements on reporting and monitoring of ICAP's credit assessment evo-	R
<ul> <li>Analytics, Athens University of Economics and Business</li> <li>Support regulatory requirements on reporting and monitoring of ICAP's credit assessment evolution data to regulators</li> <li>Support reporting to European Rating Platform (ERP/RADAR), the platform maintained by</li> </ul>	R SAS Base SQL

 $\textbf{Researcher}, \ Telephone \ Research \ Department, \ Metron \ Analysis \ S.A., \ Athens$ 

01/2015 - 10/2015

• Participate in the conduction of various research projects in the section of the telephone survey department

## **Education**

 $\label{eq:m.sc.} \textbf{M.Sc. in Business Analytics}, \ \textbf{Athens University of Economics and Business} \\ \textbf{Degree with Distinction, 8.86 / 10}$ 

10/2015 - 01/2017

Field Study Project (Master Thesis) conducted in ICAP Group:

Development of automated system in R for the following activities on default characterization data:

• Data cleansing, exploration and transformation

- Statistical reporting and visualization
- Creation of historical database and integration in optimised data schema

Part of master projects:

• Data warehousing, data management, ETL

• Statistical analyses implementing various methods, e.g. regression, classification, clustering, LASSO, PCA, Naive Bayes, etc.

• Application development using big data tools

• Data Mining, large scale optimization, visual analytics, recommender systems, business analysis

B.Sc. in Mathematics, University of Athens

10/2008 - 09/2013

• Main topics of interest: Probability Theory, Operations Research, Stochastics, Statistics

Tools

Tools

MySQL, MemSQL Hadoop, Spark

Redis, MongoDB

Neo4j

R, Python

Java, Scala

Pentaho Rapid Miner

SAS Miner

Spotfire

IBM Watson

R, Java MATLAB

#### Languages

• English: Perfect knowledge, Proficiency of Michigan, 2011

• French: Good knowledge, Paris - Sorbonne B2, 2014

## **Professional development**

e-learning courses: Coursera, edX, Datacamp

02/2015 - Present

Enhanced my programming skills and broadened my knowledge gaining hands-on experience and better understanding in several subjects and tools of data science and analytics. Full list of certifications in https://www.nikoskousiadis.com

### **Additional** info

06/2015: GMAT: Score 700